<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-13T09:53:26-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Always More Efficient]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/always-more-efficient/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-13T08:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/always-more-efficient</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em> What is something you should do less efficiently so that you can do it more thoroughly? </em></strong></p>

<p>We are always working to be more efficient - we attempt to multi-task (yes, I know it&#8217;s a myth that we truly can but
that doesn&#8217;t seem to stop folks from trying), we optimize our schedules, we plan our meetings to the minute, we are
looking to squeeze every last drop out every minute we have during the day. But at what cost? Often times, we are so
focused on being efficient that we miss important details. We lose the opportunity to truly connect and go deep
because we&#8217;re so focused on what is coming next. We should be working to squeeze every bit of connection out of those
meetings. Focusing on what we can do really well regardless of the extra effort it takes. We should be more concerned
with the value we are providing than the schedule we are keeping.</p>

<p>This next week, I am intentionally going to focus on at least 1 thing that I will be less efficient at so that I can
be more thorough. Do you know what it is you would focus on?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Profits for Good]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/profits-for-good/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T07:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/profits-for-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://driventodevelop.com/images/capitalist_pig.jpg">&#8220;Capitalism&#8221; is typically a word that evokes images of a fat business man on a pile of other people&#8217;s hard work and
money. It&#8217;s not a pretty image and certainly not one that most folks want to be associated with. No one wants to think
the profits of their efforts feed some singluarly greedy entity, personal or corporate. However, the reality of business
is that it REQUIRES profits to maintain it&#8217;s ability to run and provide the opportunity for folks to work and provide
for themselves and their families. So how do we break out of that mold? Can business be both good and profitable?</p>

<h3>Conscious Capitalism</h3>

<p>I&#8217;ve recently become aware of <a href="http://www.consciouscapitalism.org">Conscious Capitalism</a>. It was started
by John Mackey, CEO of Whole Foods, and Kip Tindell, CEO of Container Store, as a movement towards a more holistic view
of corporate responsibility to a larger audience and a deeper purpose. Basically, profits are not evil but should be
focused on the environment that produced them as a way to grow the business. To illustrate this, we have the
Stakeholder Model - whereas typical business focuses on the shareholder and customers as the main stakeholders in a
business&#8217; success, we believe in the larger perspective of stakeholders. The employees who provide value to our
customers, industry that we are working in, the suppliers who provide us with the goods we need to produce value, as
well as the community we live in. Without any one of these critical stakeholders, the company would be decreased and
less effective. These are the relationships that we should focus on and be investing in. By focusing on this larger
perspective, we are able to feed back significantly to the ecosystem that we live in.</p>

<p>For me this was a &#8220;duh&#8221; moment. Of course there&#8217;s a broader perspective (there usually is if you are paying attention)
and it was great to have a framework and vocabulary to match the things I have believed and been living for a while now.
Let me explain&#8230;</p>

<h3>Improving</h3>

<p>One of the founding ideas of <a href="http://improvingenterprises.com">Improving</a> was that we would be THE place that people want to work. A place that you can
find fullfillment and success in what you do. A place that focused on people and relationships first and foremost. This was a VERY different philosophy than what I had come thru previously in my
career. At Improving, we cared about our customers and their success as most businesses do but there was more. Our
suppliers would come and hang out with us (one in particular spends mornings at our office to have coffee and chat about
family and life). The vast majority of the user groups in the area used our facilities and were given pizza and drinks for free.
We spoke at a significant number of conferences and attended them in packs. We fundraised for the local community and
found ways to contribute time and money to the types of charities I&#8217;ve come to believe make a difference. Most of all,
people cared about each other. They truly and honestly were involved in each other&#8217;s lives both inside and outside of
work. I don&#8217;t want to paint things too perfect, they&#8217;re not. We have our share of challenges and are always looking at
ways to be better but we
have a perspective for what could be and now we have a model for speaking to that. It&#8217;s been cool to see how the things laid
out by Conscious Capitalism are what have been built into Improving from the start. And to see that something that
sounds idealistic can be a reality and, even better, a success.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time For Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/time-for-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T07:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/time-for-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Disclaimer</h3>

<p><strong><em> This is a perspective I&#8217;m currently exploring and so I&#8217;m arguing both sides. You&#8217;ve been warned. </em></strong></p>

<h2>Family</h2>

<p>When we need time for something it must be taken. It cannot be replaced or given back or returned, we consume it and it&#8217;s gone.
Often times when you need that extra time to get something done, like a meeting or conversation, we steal that time from our families.
We steal from them because they love us and will forgive us. We don&#8217;t seem to steal that time from the people we work for/with. But why is that?
Our drive to perform or excel, to be perfect at work, overrides our drive to be the same at home.
When I take that extra hour to have another meeting or to finish conversation or do another report, I&#8217;m stealing from my son or my wife. This is
an emotional representation rather than a factual one to be clear but that doesn&#8217;t make it any less accurate. Perceptions are reality.</p>

<h2>Work</h2>

<p>I was made for this. The gifts I have been given, the talents that I possess, the knowledge that I have acquired&#8230;all align to what I am doing.
I am fulfilling my purpose. I was made to work and by living up to that potential I am setting an example for my family. The provisions that we have
are because of this effort and we can enjoy them as the blessings that they truly are. When I take the time to make sure a job is done right
I am showing my children how to be diligent in their work.</p>

<p>You can&#8217;t steal what is given freely. If I put a basket of pennies somewhere with a sign
&#8220;Take as many as you need&#8221; and you take them all, it wasn&#8217;t stealing. Often times our families give freely, where our employers do not, and that&#8217;s
not stealing. This is where the recent trend of &#8220;unlimited&#8221; vacation time has started to shift that mindset but that&#8217;s a different post&#8230;</p>

<h2>Balance is NOT the goal</h2>

<p>You cannot balance two things that are fundamentally unequal. It&#8217;s like closing one eye and holding up a yellow M&amp;M until it&#8217;s the same size as the sun in the sky.
Now they&#8217;re the same, right? Looking at something thru a single dimensionality is a farce and by no means a measure of that thing. Size alone doesn&#8217;t make them the same
any more than me spending more time at work than home makes one more significant than the other.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excel is a Cul-de-sac]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/excel-is-a-cul-de-sac/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-28T08:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/excel-is-a-cul-de-sac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my recent transition, I&#8217;ve had to become even more intimate with Excel as a tool of my job. Previously I&#8217;ve used Excel
in crazy ways, as a data source for an ODBC connection or a pass thru between disconnected services, but now it&#8217;s
something to run the business on. That&#8217;s a knife that cuts both ways though.</p>

<h2>The Current State</h2>

<p>Excel is an extremely useful app and the learning curve on it is fairly low. Things you would typically do are easily
found via Google and most C-level folks have been mashing up formulas for a good hunk of time. I can safely say there
are some companies of significant size that are run off of Excel spreadsheets that are passed around via email
(don&#8217;t even get me started on the lack of Dropbox use). It works fairly well and, while seemingly creating only a small
amount of overhead, gets the job done. But there&#8217;s a big problem underlying this behavior.</p>

<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>New people. Ok, so the new people aren&#8217;t the actual problem but they surface the start of the problem. When data is pulled from a
source system into Excel it can be sliced, diced, and manipulated until it says what you need it to but that&#8217;s it. It&#8217;s
done. And it was almost always manual. Rarely is the manipulation reproducible by anyone other than the person who just
did it because that would require the use of macros and VBScript and stuff that only developers really grok. Strike #1.</p>

<p>Manipulated data is dead in Excel, like those dead tree requirements docs we have all decided were a less
than ideal way to do things. You can&#8217;t pull new data into the existing spreadsheet and have it follow the transformation to add
to the output. No, instead you pull new data and start back at square one. Strike #2.</p>

<p>Did you want to use that data in some other system or feed it back into the one that it originally came from? No joy
here. The data cannot be consumed in as easy a fashion as it was put into Excel. Sure you can get a developer to monkey
up an ODBC connection like I did before but that&#8217;s not something most executives are going to be able to pull off.
Maybe they&#8217;re able to string together a set of Excel sheets that refer to each other and use the data between them but
that&#8217;s a tangled and fragile web. And given the prior two issues, we know what sort of overhead maintaining that is
going to be when it comes time to update with new data. Strike #3.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>I&#8217;m not against using Excel, heck, I do it on a pretty regular basis. I&#8217;m against it&#8217;s overuse; the crutch that it
becomes when folks just want a one off thing (until it isn&#8217;t), for just a few people (until there&#8217;s more), and won&#8217;t
need again (until they do). When you need something more, step up and move out of your comfort zone, find a tool that
supports what you need and isn&#8217;t a three strike offender.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wisdom Not Just Knowledge]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wisdom-not-just-knowledge/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T08:06:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wisdom-not-just-knowledge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sites like quora are time sinks for the virtual wisdom they provide. They&#8217;re like brain candy. Don&#8217;t get me wrong, I
love candy too, but it&#8217;s no substitute for a good meal. People are more interested in collecting knowledge and parading
it around as wisdom rather than acting upon it to discover the true nature of that knowledge. Experience is the only
true impartation of wisdom. Everything else is just academic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scrum as Cake Analogy]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/scrum-as-cake-analogy/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T09:46:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/scrum-as-cake-analogy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve used this analogy a couple of times when explaining agile adoption, specifically Scrum, to folks so I wanted to put
it here for reference.</p>

<h2>The Analogy</h2>

<p>Imagine for a minute that you&#8217;ve never baked a cake before but you want to learn how. I give you a recipe to follow,
it&#8217;s my grandmothers recipe and everyone agrees she makes killer cake, and it&#8217;s simple so I know it&#8217;s a good one for you
to start with. You take a look at the recipe and say, &#8220;I actually don&#8217;t like to use flour so I&#8217;m going to skip that&#8221;.
Then you mention that vegetable oil isn&#8217;t really something you use so you&#8217;re going to substitute cooking spray instead.
You mix things up, bake it, and the cake comes out a mess. You throw your hands up in disgust and announce that cake
baking is horrible and doesn&#8217;t work. Was there anything wrong with the recipe? Or was it just
your inability to follow it that created the outcome you got? Who&#8217;s responsible for the failure?</p>

<h2>Advice</h2>

<p>Going by the book allows for an understanding of all the pieces; how they operate, what their intent is, and why they&#8217;re
important. You can&#8217;t simply start replacing bits and pieces without all that understanding or you&#8217;re likely to spoil the
outcome. Scrum works. Scrummerfall or Waterscrum or whatever kind of duct-tape and bailing wire setup you&#8217;ve cobbled
together may, or may not, work. But that&#8217;s not the fault of the process that you&#8217;ve cribbed from.
To be fair, I do understand that there are challenges that each environment presents. We can&#8217;t always get the support we
need to make everything happen but let&#8217;s lay the blame where it belongs; us not the process. The
whole purpose of Scrum is to make these things visible so you can deal with them and get moving on the things that
create real value.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working Body Means A Free Mind]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/working-body-means-a-free-mind/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T09:17:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/working-body-means-a-free-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spend a vast majority of my week positioned squarely on my butt. It&#8217;s a sedentary life, which is why I&#8217;ve had to start
working out again, but it&#8217;s one that I love and get paid to live. Not that I&#8217;m not phyically capable of working to earn
a living, it&#8217;s simply that someone values my mind more than my body at this point. I&#8217;m ok with that but I&#8217;ve come to
realize that these two things aren&#8217;t as separate as I used to think. I have things I do to keep both in line and they
have become way more important as I&#8217;ve grown older (and hopefully wiser).</p>

<p>No, this is not another post about exercise - at least not by the standard definition of that word. It&#8217;s more about the
things we need to do to exercise our minds and to have &#8220;quiet times&#8221; for that. I love being outdoors and my favorite activity of the week is mowing the lawn. It&#8217;s a time for me to do some rote work that frees my mind up to wander and explore.
It&#8217;s prayer time, reflection time, an opportunity to process and
expand on the ideas banging around inside my head. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='My wife likes to tease me about it being the loudest quiet time imaginable. '> My wife likes to tease me about it being the loudest quiet time imaginable. </span></p>

<p>I realized that this time has allowed me to clarify a lot of my thoughts. It allows me time to think thru what is going
on in my life and work. I can exand ideas and game-film interactions that I know are coming so that the best possible
results can be achieved. Realizing all this led me to a few other interesting thoughts&#8230;what would it take to cause me
to hire someone to mow? It&#8217;s time that I value greatly and would have to replace in some other way to achieve the same
level of thoughtfulness so it&#8217;s trade off would be a big one. So then, what else can I delegate to allow me to continue
mowing? At this point, I&#8217;m not willing to outsource my family or my job so I guess I&#8217;ll have to keep thinking about it.
While mowing, of course.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Chapter]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/a-new-chapter/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T18:01:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/a-new-chapter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it&#8217;s been a while since I posted (a typical excuse, right?) but I&#8217;ve been pretty busy lately. Let me fill you
in&#8230;</p>

<p>This summer our company decide to create additional positions for the VP of consulting since we had grown to
over 90 consultants and I was promoted to one of those positions. It was a great opportunity for me to better connect
with a number of our folks but also for me to increase my involvement in the business aspects of the company. I enjoy
meeting with everyone and talking, not only about what&#8217;s going on with their client or our company, but also helping
them in figuring out what their career path looks like and where they want to go. It&#8217;s something that I&#8217;m really
passionate about; the future.</p>

<p>So even more recently, our president, Barry Rogers, decided to semi-retire. He and his wife have always wanted to have a different
work-life ratio than what they currently enjoyed and so are making a change. You can read a little more about their plans as well as their upcoming/on-going adventures
at <a href="http://webebalanced.com/">We Be Balanced</a>. Given this decision, it was announced that I will be taking over as president beginning in 2013. I&#8217;m excited about the direction our company is heading and the opportunity to help
shape and steer things. I realize this means I will have to prioritize my focus a little differently and, while I&#8217;m
unlikely to give up on my late night coding sessions entirely, they will probably become a little less frequent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Know]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-23T16:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saying &#8220;I don&#8217;t know&#8221; is hard. It&#8217;s an admission of a shortcoming, a lack. It says, &#8220;I lack knowledge&#8221; or &#8220;I lack understanding&#8221;.
Not saying it is worse though. Making up some sort of answer says the same thing, shows the same lack, but it includes
a lie; an inability to admit reality or be perceived as inadequate. News flash: we all are inadequate (on a way more frequent basis
than we&#8217;d like to admit). The difference is you choose to ignore reality. A lack of knowledge is something that could possibly be
remedied. But lying about realities, that&#8217;s intrinsic, something fundamental and not something that you can easily
fix. Oh, and the person you&#8217;re talking to will know it - they just might be polite enough not to say anything. Do yourself a favor;
just say &#8220;I don&#8217;t know&#8221; and we can both go from there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wear Your Career Uniform]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T08:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back I had multiple client and business needs that required me to dress up a little more than I usually do.
After enduring the standard, &#8220;You got an interview or something?&#8221; wise cracks that are inevitable, I began to notice
a change behaviors in a couple of ways. Now I want to be clear, I believe the old maxim, <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;The clothes make the man&#8221; is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. '> &#8220;The clothes make the man&#8221; is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. </span> But&#8230;the clothes are an outwards manifestation of something
internal. They don&#8217;t make you work any harder or be more productive but if your job involves appearances in any way,
you&#8217;re at a disadvantage. They make people see you in a particular way, like it or not, we are a prejudicial people.
You make snap judgements; everyone does. Fighting reality is futile (but that&#8217;s another post). Give it a shot yourself
- take 3 weeks and shift how you dress, then see what differences have come up in both your personal attitude and that
  of those around you&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughtful Actions]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-19T18:42:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are regularly told that we should &#8220;think before we speak&#8221;, however, I believe it
to be equally important that we think before we act. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Never be dictated to by expediency. '> Never be dictated to by expediency. </span> was a regular saying from my father.
And I have to say that, historically in my life at least, he&#8217;s been correct. Now
I know that we all end up in situations where we need to make snap decisions or
something needs to be handled in the immediate - that&#8217;s just life but there are
also times when some reflection and careful thought can be afforded.
Unfortunately, no one has every taught me what to actually do with that time.</p>

<h2>The Canvas</h2>

<p>So if I&#8217;m supposed to be thoughtful about what it is I do in specific situations, how do I achieve that? Well, I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s the solution for everyone but I&#8217;ve got a template that works for me and I wanted to share with you all. You can find it at <a href="http://journal.driventodevelop.com">http://journal.driventodevelop.com</a>. It&#8217;s a pretty simple and self-explanatory template (if you need a hint there&#8217;s an instruction box in the top right that I&#8217;m working to make contextual help). I needed a quick way to throw some security on it so it uses Twitter for authentication but I assure you I&#8217;m not collecting any kind of info otherwise. In the past couple weeks, I have been surprised how much this has helped me with situations I was experiencing and brought things to a significantly better conclusion that I had hoped for at the outset. Give it a shot and let me know what you think&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Disruptive]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T09:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve <a href="http://twitter.com/davidmohara/status/144168515207823361">tweeted</a> before about this but felt, as is often the case, that it could be percieved as a bit
flippant with regards to how I feel about the startups I encounter. While those
who know me will agree that I rarely take myself too seriously, I am serious
about new ideas and how they could change things but I don&#8217;t need you to tell me
that. Let me back up a second&#8230;</p>

<h2>Flys Buzz</h2>

<p>&#8220;Startups don&#8217;t buzz, flys do; and it&#8217;s usually around horseshit&#8221; Far too often
I have an idea pitched to me that is little more than a haphazard collection of
buzzwords and acronyms. If your idea needs something like that to make it
attractive, you need a new idea. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Making it &#8220;social&#8221; or using gamification will only work if your idea doesn&#8217;t suck to begin with. '>Making it &#8220;social&#8221; or using gamification will only work if your idea doesn&#8217;t suck to begin with.</span> Start there and <strong>then</strong> work
your way into the other bits, not the other way around. That&#8217;s the idea I want
pitched to me. And don&#8217;t tell me &#8220;I think&#8221; this or that, I can&#8217;t measure &#8220;I
think&#8221;. Show me some sort of actual data - even if it&#8217;s a SWAG it at least shows
me you&#8217;ve thought things thru enough to put numbers around. Ok, enough of a side
rant.</p>

<h2>Labels</h2>

<p>Now to the main point of my tweet. The reason why I will stop listening when you
use the term &#8220;disruptive&#8221; in your pitch is that disruptive
can only be applied in hindsight, thru the lens of
success. Twitter didn&#8217;t set out to be disruptive, Amazon wasn&#8217;t bankrolled
because they were disruptive, they set out to solve a problem. That&#8217;s
what you need to focus on: solving someone&#8217;s pain. If you can show me how you
deliver value in that direction (and how you intend to reach out to people with that pain), then I&#8217;m
interested. So now, go sit down and rethink your elevator pitch without using
a single buzzword - then give me a call cause I&#8217;d love to hear it&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clean Slate]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/clean-slate/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T14:21:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/clean-slate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s not you&#8230;it&#8217;s me. I have been meaning to do this for a long time and while I don&#8217;t think there is ever a <em>right</em> time for a break up like this, I think the time is now.</p>

<h2>Calling It</h2>

<p>There have a been a lot of changes in my life recently and I think that they are
beginning to effect my perspective on life. Honestly, I sort of hope that they
do. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Life is short. So damn short, in fact, that it is not worth running thru if you&#8217;re not enjoying what little time we have on this rock.'>Life is short. So damn short, in fact, that it is not worth running thru if you&#8217;re not enjoying what little time we have on this rock.</span>
  To that end, I am rebooting my blogging life. The old stuff will remain
  <a href="http://blog.davidohara.net">here</a> but my new adventures and musings will be here. Maybe at
  some point I&#8217;ll combine the two domains in some non-breaking way but right now I don&#8217;t want the hassle
  so I&#8217;m declaring blog bankruptcy and just moving forward.</p>

<h2>New Setup</h2>

<p>Like so many others, I have decided to give <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>
a shot. I won&#8217;t bother you will any details since so many others have done
a great job of explaining how to get things up and going but I can say that so far I&#8217;ve been very impressed. Initially, my intention is to blog at least once a week and see where that takes me. They&#8217;re not going to be long posts (I&#8217;m hoping this will help me in my follow thru) and I hope that they&#8217;ll be more than semi-coherent ramblings. Guess we will have to see&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
