<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-27T08:24:12-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Chapter]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/a-new-chapter/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T18:01:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/a-new-chapter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it&#8217;s been a while since I posted (a typical excuse, right?) but I&#8217;ve been pretty busy lately. Let me fill you
in&#8230;</p>

<p>This summer our company decide to create additional positions for the VP of consulting since we had grown to
over 90 consultants and I was promoted to one of those positions. It was a great opportunity for me to better connect
with a number of our folks but also for me to increase my involvement in the business aspects of the company. I enjoy
meeting with everyone and talking, not only about what&#8217;s going on with their client or our company, but also helping
them in figuring out what their career path looks like and where they want to go. It&#8217;s something that I&#8217;m really
passionate about; the future.</p>

<p>So even more recently, our president, Barry Rogers, decided to semi-retire. He and his wife have always wanted to have a different
work-life ratio than what they currently enjoyed and so are making a change. You can read a little more about their plans as well as their upcoming/on-going adventures
at <a href="http://webebalanced.com/">We Be Balanced</a>. Given this decision, it was announced that I will be taking over as president beginning in 2013. I&#8217;m excited about the direction our company is heading and the opportunity to help
shape and steer things. I realize this means I will have to prioritize my focus a little differently and, while I&#8217;m
unlikely to give up on my late night coding sessions entirely, they will probably become a little less frequent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Know]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-23T16:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saying &#8220;I don&#8217;t know&#8221; is hard. It&#8217;s an admission of a shortcoming, a lack. It says, &#8220;I lack knowledge&#8221; or &#8220;I lack understanding&#8221;.
Not saying it is worse though. Making up some sort of answer says the same thing, shows the same lack, but it includes
a lie; an inability to admit reality or be perceived as inadequate. News flash: we all are inadequate (on a way more frequent basis
than we&#8217;d like to admit). The difference is you choose to ignore reality. A lack of knowledge is something that could possibly be
remedied. But lying about realities, that&#8217;s intrinsic, something fundamental and not something that you can easily
fix. Oh, and the person you&#8217;re talking to will know it - they just might be polite enough not to say anything. Do yourself a favor;
just say &#8220;I don&#8217;t know&#8221; and we can both go from there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wear Your Career Uniform]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T08:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back I had multiple client and business needs that required me to dress up a little more than I usually do.
After enduring the standard, &#8220;You got an interview or something?&#8221; wise cracks that are inevitable, I began to notice
a change behaviors in a couple of ways. Now I want to be clear, I believe the old maxim, <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;The clothes make the man&#8221; is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. '> &#8220;The clothes make the man&#8221; is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. </span> But&#8230;the clothes are an outwards manifestation of something
internal. They don&#8217;t make you work any harder or be more productive but if your job involves appearances in any way,
you&#8217;re at a disadvantage. They make people see you in a particular way, like it or not, we are a prejudicial people.
You make snap judgements; everyone does. Fighting reality is futile (but that&#8217;s another post). Give it a shot yourself
- take 3 weeks and shift how you dress, then see what differences have come up in both your personal attitude and that
  of those around you&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughtful Actions]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-19T18:42:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are regularly told that we should &#8220;think before we speak&#8221;, however, I believe it
to be equally important that we think before we act. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Never be dictated to by expediency. '> Never be dictated to by expediency. </span> was a regular saying from my father.
And I have to say that, historically in my life at least, he&#8217;s been correct. Now
I know that we all end up in situations where we need to make snap decisions or
something needs to be handled in the immediate - that&#8217;s just life but there are
also times when some reflection and careful thought can be afforded.
Unfortunately, no one has every taught me what to actually do with that time.</p>

<h2>The Canvas</h2>

<p>So if I&#8217;m supposed to be thoughtful about what it is I do in specific situations, how do I achieve that? Well, I don&#8217;t know if it&#8217;s the solution for everyone but I&#8217;ve got a template that works for me and I wanted to share with you all. You can find it at <a href="http://journal.driventodevelop.com">http://journal.driventodevelop.com</a>. It&#8217;s a pretty simple and self-explanatory template (if you need a hint there&#8217;s an instruction box in the top right that I&#8217;m working to make contextual help). I needed a quick way to throw some security on it so it uses Twitter for authentication but I assure you I&#8217;m not collecting any kind of info otherwise. In the past couple weeks, I have been surprised how much this has helped me with situations I was experiencing and brought things to a significantly better conclusion that I had hoped for at the outset. Give it a shot and let me know what you think&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Disruptive]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T09:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve <a href="http://twitter.com/davidmohara/status/144168515207823361">tweeted</a> before about this but felt, as is often the case, that it could be percieved as a bit
flippant with regards to how I feel about the startups I encounter. While those
who know me will agree that I rarely take myself too seriously, I am serious
about new ideas and how they could change things but I don&#8217;t need you to tell me
that. Let me back up a second&#8230;</p>

<h2>Flys Buzz</h2>

<p>&#8220;Startups don&#8217;t buzz, flys do; and it&#8217;s usually around horseshit&#8221; Far too often
I have an idea pitched to me that is little more than a haphazard collection of
buzzwords and acronyms. If your idea needs something like that to make it
attractive, you need a new idea. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Making it &#8220;social&#8221; or using gamification will only work if your idea doesn&#8217;t suck to begin with. '>Making it &#8220;social&#8221; or using gamification will only work if your idea doesn&#8217;t suck to begin with.</span> Start there and <strong>then</strong> work
your way into the other bits, not the other way around. That&#8217;s the idea I want
pitched to me. And don&#8217;t tell me &#8220;I think&#8221; this or that, I can&#8217;t measure &#8220;I
think&#8221;. Show me some sort of actual data - even if it&#8217;s a SWAG it at least shows
me you&#8217;ve thought things thru enough to put numbers around. Ok, enough of a side
rant.</p>

<h2>Labels</h2>

<p>Now to the main point of my tweet. The reason why I will stop listening when you
use the term &#8220;disruptive&#8221; in your pitch is that disruptive
can only be applied in hindsight, thru the lens of
success. Twitter didn&#8217;t set out to be disruptive, Amazon wasn&#8217;t bankrolled
because they were disruptive, they set out to solve a problem. That&#8217;s
what you need to focus on: solving someone&#8217;s pain. If you can show me how you
deliver value in that direction (and how you intend to reach out to people with that pain), then I&#8217;m
interested. So now, go sit down and rethink your elevator pitch without using
a single buzzword - then give me a call cause I&#8217;d love to hear it&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clean Slate]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/clean-slate/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-01T14:21:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/clean-slate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s not you&#8230;it&#8217;s me. I have been meaning to do this for a long time and while I don&#8217;t think there is ever a <em>right</em> time for a break up like this, I think the time is now.</p>

<h2>Calling It</h2>

<p>There have a been a lot of changes in my life recently and I think that they are
beginning to effect my perspective on life. Honestly, I sort of hope that they
do. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Life is short. So damn short, in fact, that it is not worth running thru if you&#8217;re not enjoying what little time we have on this rock.'>Life is short. So damn short, in fact, that it is not worth running thru if you&#8217;re not enjoying what little time we have on this rock.</span>
  To that end, I am rebooting my blogging life. The old stuff will remain
  <a href="http://blog.davidohara.net">here</a> but my new adventures and musings will be here. Maybe at
  some point I&#8217;ll combine the two domains in some non-breaking way but right now I don&#8217;t want the hassle
  so I&#8217;m declaring blog bankruptcy and just moving forward.</p>

<h2>New Setup</h2>

<p>Like so many others, I have decided to give <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>
a shot. I won&#8217;t bother you will any details since so many others have done
a great job of explaining how to get things up and going but I can say that so far I&#8217;ve been very impressed. Initially, my intention is to blog at least once a week and see where that takes me. They&#8217;re not going to be long posts (I&#8217;m hoping this will help me in my follow thru) and I hope that they&#8217;ll be more than semi-coherent ramblings. Guess we will have to see&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
