<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: rant | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/rant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-04T00:54:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Disruptive]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T09:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve <a href="http://twitter.com/davidmohara/status/144168515207823361">tweeted</a> before about this but felt, as is often the case, that it could be percieved as a bit
flippant with regards to how I feel about the startups I encounter. While those
who know me will agree that I rarely take myself too seriously, I am serious
about new ideas and how they could change things but I don&rsquo;t need you to tell me
that. Let me back up a second&hellip;</p>

<h2>Flys Buzz</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Startups don&rsquo;t buzz, flys do; and it&rsquo;s usually around horseshit&rdquo; Far too often
I have an idea pitched to me that is little more than a haphazard collection of
buzzwords and acronyms. If your idea needs something like that to make it
attractive, you need a new idea. Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "} Start there and <strong>then</strong> work
your way into the other bits, not the other way around. That&rsquo;s the idea I want
pitched to me. And don&rsquo;t tell me "I think&rdquo; this or that, I can&rsquo;t measure &ldquo;I
think&rdquo;. Show me some sort of actual data &ndash; even if it&rsquo;s a SWAG it at least shows
me you&rsquo;ve thought things thru enough to put numbers around. Ok, enough of a side
rant.</p>

<h2>Labels</h2>

<p>Now to the main point of my tweet. The reason why I will stop listening when you
use the term &ldquo;disruptive&rdquo; in your pitch is that disruptive
can only be applied in hindsight, thru the lens of
success. Twitter didn&rsquo;t set out to be disruptive, Amazon wasn&rsquo;t bankrolled
because they were disruptive, they set out to solve a problem. That&rsquo;s
what you need to focus on: solving someone&rsquo;s pain. If you can show me how you
deliver value in that direction (and how you intend to reach out to people with that pain), then I&rsquo;m
interested. So now, go sit down and rethink your elevator pitch without using
a single buzzword &ndash; then give me a call cause I&rsquo;d love to hear it&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
