<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: improving | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/improving/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-04T01:06:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Profits for Good]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/profits-for-good/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-06T07:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/profits-for-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/capitalist_pig.jpg">&ldquo;Capitalism&rdquo; is typically a word that evokes images of a fat business man on a pile of other people&rsquo;s hard work and
money. It&rsquo;s not a pretty image and certainly not one that most folks want to be associated with. No one wants to think
the profits of their efforts feed some singluarly greedy entity, personal or corporate. However, the reality of business
is that it REQUIRES profits to maintain it&rsquo;s ability to run and provide the opportunity for folks to work and provide
for themselves and their families. So how do we break out of that mold? Can business be both good and profitable?</p>

<h3>Conscious Capitalism</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve recently become aware of <a href="http://www.consciouscapitalism.org">Conscious Capitalism</a>. It was started
by John Mackey, CEO of Whole Foods, and Kip Tindell, CEO of Container Store, as a movement towards a more holistic view
of corporate responsibility to a larger audience and a deeper purpose. Basically, profits are not evil but should be
focused on the environment that produced them as a way to grow the business. To illustrate this, we have the
Stakeholder Model &ndash; whereas typical business focuses on the shareholder and customers as the main stakeholders in a
business' success, we believe in the larger perspective of stakeholders. The employees who provide value to our
customers, industry that we are working in, the suppliers who provide us with the goods we need to produce value, as
well as the community we live in. Without any one of these critical stakeholders, the company would be decreased and
less effective. These are the relationships that we should focus on and be investing in. By focusing on this larger
perspective, we are able to feed back significantly to the ecosystem that we live in.</p>

<p>For me this was a &ldquo;duh&rdquo; moment. Of course there&rsquo;s a broader perspective (there usually is if you are paying attention)
and it was great to have a framework and vocabulary to match the things I have believed and been living for a while now.
Let me explain&hellip;</p>

<h3>Improving</h3>

<p>One of the founding ideas of <a href="http://improvingenterprises.com">Improving</a> was that we would be THE place that people want to work. A place that you can
find fullfillment and success in what you do. A place that focused on people and relationships first and foremost. This was a VERY different philosophy than what I had come thru previously in my
career. At Improving, we cared about our customers and their success as most businesses do but there was more. Our
suppliers would come and hang out with us (one in particular spends mornings at our office to have coffee and chat about
family and life). The vast majority of the user groups in the area used our facilities and were given pizza and drinks for free.
We spoke at a significant number of conferences and attended them in packs. We fundraised for the local community and
found ways to contribute time and money to the types of charities I&rsquo;ve come to believe make a difference. Most of all,
people cared about each other. They truly and honestly were involved in each other&rsquo;s lives both inside and outside of
work. I don&rsquo;t want to paint things too perfect, they&rsquo;re not. We have our share of challenges and are always looking at
ways to be better but we
have a perspective for what could be and now we have a model for speaking to that. It&rsquo;s been cool to see how the things laid
out by Conscious Capitalism are what have been built into Improving from the start. And to see that something that
sounds idealistic can be a reality and, even better, a success.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A New Chapter]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/a-new-chapter/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T18:01:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/a-new-chapter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I know it&rsquo;s been a while since I posted (a typical excuse, right?) but I&rsquo;ve been pretty busy lately. Let me fill you
in&hellip;</p>

<p>This summer our company decide to create additional positions for the VP of consulting since we had grown to
over 90 consultants and I was promoted to one of those positions. It was a great opportunity for me to better connect
with a number of our folks but also for me to increase my involvement in the business aspects of the company. I enjoy
meeting with everyone and talking, not only about what&rsquo;s going on with their client or our company, but also helping
them in figuring out what their career path looks like and where they want to go. It&rsquo;s something that I&rsquo;m really
passionate about; the future.</p>

<p>So even more recently, our president, Barry Rogers, decided to semi-retire. He and his wife have always wanted to have a different
work-life ratio than what they currently enjoyed and so are making a change. You can read a little more about their plans as well as their upcoming/on-going adventures
at <a href="http://webebalanced.com/">We Be Balanced</a>. Given this decision, it was announced that I will be taking over as president beginning in 2013. I&rsquo;m excited about the direction our company is heading and the opportunity to help
shape and steer things. I realize this means I will have to prioritize my focus a little differently and, while I&rsquo;m
unlikely to give up on my late night coding sessions entirely, they will probably become a little less frequent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
