<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apps | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/apps/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-21T15:22:29-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughtful Actions]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-19T18:42:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are regularly told that we should "think before we speak", however, I believe it
to be equally important that we think before we act. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Never be dictated to by expediency. '> Never be dictated to by expediency. </span> was a regular saying from my father.
And I have to say that, historically in my life at least, he's been correct. Now
I know that we all end up in situations where we need to make snap decisions or
something needs to be handled in the immediate - that's just life but there are
also times when some reflection and careful thought can be afforded.
Unfortunately, no one has every taught me what to actually do with that time.</p>

<h2>The Canvas</h2>

<p>So if I'm supposed to be thoughtful about what it is I do in specific situations, how do I achieve that? Well, I don't know if it's the solution for everyone but I've got a template that works for me and I wanted to share with you all. You can find it at <a href="http://journal.driventodevelop.com">http://journal.driventodevelop.com</a>. It's a pretty simple and self-explanatory template (if you need a hint there's an instruction box in the top right that I'm working to make contextual help). I needed a quick way to throw some security on it so it uses Twitter for authentication but I assure you I'm not collecting any kind of info otherwise. In the past couple weeks, I have been surprised how much this has helped me with situations I was experiencing and brought things to a significantly better conclusion that I had hoped for at the outset. Give it a shot and let me know what you think...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
