<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-28T12:25:08-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time For Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/time-for-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T07:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/time-for-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Disclaimer</h3>

<p><strong><em> This is a perspective I&rsquo;m currently exploring and so I&rsquo;m arguing both sides. You&rsquo;ve been warned. </em></strong></p>

<h2>Family</h2>

<p>When we need time for something it must be taken. It cannot be replaced or given back or returned, we consume it and it&rsquo;s gone.
Often times when you need that extra time to get something done, like a meeting or conversation, we steal that time from our families.
We steal from them because they love us and will forgive us. We don&rsquo;t seem to steal that time from the people we work for/with. But why is that?
Our drive to perform or excel, to be perfect at work, overrides our drive to be the same at home.
When I take that extra hour to have another meeting or to finish conversation or do another report, I&rsquo;m stealing from my son or my wife. This is
an emotional representation rather than a factual one to be clear but that doesn&rsquo;t make it any less accurate. Perceptions are reality.</p>

<h2>Work</h2>

<p>I was made for this. The gifts I have been given, the talents that I possess, the knowledge that I have acquired&hellip;all align to what I am doing.
I am fulfilling my purpose. I was made to work and by living up to that potential I am setting an example for my family. The provisions that we have
are because of this effort and we can enjoy them as the blessings that they truly are. When I take the time to make sure a job is done right
I am showing my children how to be diligent in their work.</p>

<p>You can&rsquo;t steal what is given freely. If I put a basket of pennies somewhere with a sign
&ldquo;Take as many as you need&rdquo; and you take them all, it wasn&rsquo;t stealing. Often times our families give freely, where our employers do not, and that&rsquo;s
not stealing. This is where the recent trend of &ldquo;unlimited&rdquo; vacation time has started to shift that mindset but that&rsquo;s a different post&hellip;</p>

<h2>Balance is NOT the goal</h2>

<p>You cannot balance two things that are fundamentally unequal. It&rsquo;s like closing one eye and holding up a yellow M&amp;M until it&rsquo;s the same size as the sun in the sky.
Now they&rsquo;re the same, right? Looking at something thru a single dimensionality is a farce and by no means a measure of that thing. Size alone doesn&rsquo;t make them the same
any more than me spending more time at work than home makes one more significant than the other.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
