<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts, | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-04T01:06:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scrum as Cake Analogy]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/scrum-as-cake-analogy/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-31T09:46:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/scrum-as-cake-analogy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve used this analogy a couple of times when explaining agile adoption, specifically Scrum, to folks so I wanted to put
it here for reference.</p>

<h2>The Analogy</h2>

<p>Imagine for a minute that you&rsquo;ve never baked a cake before but you want to learn how. I give you a recipe to follow,
it&rsquo;s my grandmothers recipe and everyone agrees she makes killer cake, and it&rsquo;s simple so I know it&rsquo;s a good one for you
to start with. You take a look at the recipe and say, &ldquo;I actually don&rsquo;t like to use flour so I&rsquo;m going to skip that&rdquo;.
Then you mention that vegetable oil isn&rsquo;t really something you use so you&rsquo;re going to substitute cooking spray instead.
You mix things up, bake it, and the cake comes out a mess. You throw your hands up in disgust and announce that cake
baking is horrible and doesn&rsquo;t work. Was there anything wrong with the recipe? Or was it just
your inability to follow it that created the outcome you got? Who&rsquo;s responsible for the failure?</p>

<h2>Advice</h2>

<p>Going by the book allows for an understanding of all the pieces; how they operate, what their intent is, and why they&rsquo;re
important. You can&rsquo;t simply start replacing bits and pieces without all that understanding or you&rsquo;re likely to spoil the
outcome. Scrum works. Scrummerfall or Waterscrum or whatever kind of duct-tape and bailing wire setup you&rsquo;ve cobbled
together may, or may not, work. But that&rsquo;s not the fault of the process that you&rsquo;ve cribbed from.
To be fair, I do understand that there are challenges that each environment presents. We can&rsquo;t always get the support we
need to make everything happen but let&rsquo;s lay the blame where it belongs; us not the process. The
whole purpose of Scrum is to make these things visible so you can deal with them and get moving on the things that
create real value.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
