<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-04T17:45:16-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Know]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-23T16:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saying "I don't know" is hard. It's an admission of a shortcoming, a lack. It says, "I lack knowledge" or "I lack understanding".
Not saying it is worse though. Making up some sort of answer says the same thing, shows the same lack, but it includes
a lie; an inability to admit reality or be perceived as inadequate. News flash: we all are inadequate (on a way more frequent basis
than we'd like to admit). The difference is you choose to ignore reality. A lack of knowledge is something that could possibly be
remedied. But lying about realities, that's intrinsic, something fundamental and not something that you can easily
fix. Oh, and the person you're talking to will know it - they just might be polite enough not to say anything. Do yourself a favor;
just say "I don't know" and we can both go from there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wear Your Career Uniform]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T08:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back I had multiple client and business needs that required me to dress up a little more than I usually do.
After enduring the standard, "You got an interview or something?" wise cracks that are inevitable, I began to notice
a change behaviors in a couple of ways. Now I want to be clear, I believe the old maxim, <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;The clothes make the man&#8221; is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. '> "The clothes make the man" is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. </span> But...the clothes are an outwards manifestation of something
internal. They don't make you work any harder or be more productive but if your job involves appearances in any way,
you're at a disadvantage. They make people see you in a particular way, like it or not, we are a prejudicial people.
You make snap judgements; everyone does. Fighting reality is futile (but that's another post). Give it a shot yourself
- take 3 weeks and shift how you dress, then see what differences have come up in both your personal attitude and that
  of those around you...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughtful Actions]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-19T18:42:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/thoughtful-actions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are regularly told that we should "think before we speak", however, I believe it
to be equally important that we think before we act. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Never be dictated to by expediency. '> Never be dictated to by expediency. </span> was a regular saying from my father.
And I have to say that, historically in my life at least, he's been correct. Now
I know that we all end up in situations where we need to make snap decisions or
something needs to be handled in the immediate - that's just life but there are
also times when some reflection and careful thought can be afforded.
Unfortunately, no one has every taught me what to actually do with that time.</p>

<h2>The Canvas</h2>

<p>So if I'm supposed to be thoughtful about what it is I do in specific situations, how do I achieve that? Well, I don't know if it's the solution for everyone but I've got a template that works for me and I wanted to share with you all. You can find it at <a href="http://journal.driventodevelop.com">http://journal.driventodevelop.com</a>. It's a pretty simple and self-explanatory template (if you need a hint there's an instruction box in the top right that I'm working to make contextual help). I needed a quick way to throw some security on it so it uses Twitter for authentication but I assure you I'm not collecting any kind of info otherwise. In the past couple weeks, I have been surprised how much this has helped me with situations I was experiencing and brought things to a significantly better conclusion that I had hoped for at the outset. Give it a shot and let me know what you think...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Being Disruptive]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-05T09:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/being-disruptive</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've <a href="http://twitter.com/davidmohara/status/144168515207823361">tweeted</a> before about this but felt, as is often the case, that it could be percieved as a bit
flippant with regards to how I feel about the startups I encounter. While those
who know me will agree that I rarely take myself too seriously, I am serious
about new ideas and how they could change things but I don't need you to tell me
that. Let me back up a second...</p>

<h2>Flys Buzz</h2>

<p>"Startups don't buzz, flys do; and it's usually around horseshit" Far too often
I have an idea pitched to me that is little more than a haphazard collection of
buzzwords and acronyms. If your idea needs something like that to make it
attractive, you need a new idea. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='Making it &#8220;social&#8221; or using gamification will only work if your idea doesn&#8217;t suck to begin with. '>Making it "social" or using gamification will only work if your idea doesn't suck to begin with.</span> Start there and <strong>then</strong> work
your way into the other bits, not the other way around. That's the idea I want
pitched to me. And don't tell me "I think" this or that, I can't measure "I
think". Show me some sort of actual data - even if it's a SWAG it at least shows
me you've thought things thru enough to put numbers around. Ok, enough of a side
rant.</p>

<h2>Labels</h2>

<p>Now to the main point of my tweet. The reason why I will stop listening when you
use the term "disruptive" in your pitch is that disruptive
can only be applied in hindsight, thru the lens of
success. Twitter didn't set out to be disruptive, Amazon wasn't bankrolled
because they were disruptive, they set out to solve a problem. That's
what you need to focus on: solving someone's pain. If you can show me how you
deliver value in that direction (and how you intend to reach out to people with that pain), then I'm
interested. So now, go sit down and rethink your elevator pitch without using
a single buzzword - then give me a call cause I'd love to hear it...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
