<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-28T15:37:09-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excel is a Cul-de-sac]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/excel-is-a-cul-de-sac/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-28T08:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/excel-is-a-cul-de-sac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my recent transition, I've had to become even more intimate with Excel as a tool of my job. Previously I've used Excel
in crazy ways, as a data source for an ODBC connection or a pass thru between disconnected services, but now it's
something to run the business on. That's a knife that cuts both ways though.</p>

<h2>The Current State</h2>

<p>Excel is an extremely useful app and the learning curve on it is fairly low. Things you would typically do are easily
found via Google and most C-level folks have been mashing up formulas for a good hunk of time. I can safely say there
are some companies of significant size that are run off of Excel spreadsheets that are passed around via email
(don't even get me started on the lack of Dropbox use). It works fairly well and, while seemingly creating only a small
amount of overhead, gets the job done. But there's a big problem underlying this behavior.</p>

<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>New people. Ok, so the new people aren't the actual problem but they surface the start of the problem. When data is pulled from a
source system into Excel it can be sliced, diced, and manipulated until it says what you need it to but that's it. It's
done. And it was almost always manual. Rarely is the manipulation reproducible by anyone other than the person who just
did it because that would require the use of macros and VBScript and stuff that only developers really grok. Strike #1.</p>

<p>Manipulated data is dead in Excel, like those dead tree requirements docs we have all decided were a less
than ideal way to do things. You can't pull new data into the existing spreadsheet and have it follow the transformation to add
to the output. No, instead you pull new data and start back at square one. Strike #2.</p>

<p>Did you want to use that data in some other system or feed it back into the one that it originally came from? No joy
here. The data cannot be consumed in as easy a fashion as it was put into Excel. Sure you can get a developer to monkey
up an ODBC connection like I did before but that's not something most executives are going to be able to pull off.
Maybe they're able to string together a set of Excel sheets that refer to each other and use the data between them but
that's a tangled and fragile web. And given the prior two issues, we know what sort of overhead maintaining that is
going to be when it comes time to update with new data. Strike #3.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>I'm not against using Excel, heck, I do it on a pretty regular basis. I'm against it's overuse; the crutch that it
becomes when folks just want a one off thing (until it isn't), for just a few people (until there's more), and won't
need again (until they do). When you need something more, step up and move out of your comfort zone, find a tool that
supports what you need and isn't a three strike offender.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wisdom Not Just Knowledge]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wisdom-not-just-knowledge/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-15T08:06:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wisdom-not-just-knowledge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Sites like quora are time sinks for the virtual wisdom they provide. They're like brain candy. Don't get me wrong, I
love candy too, but it's no substitute for a good meal. People are more interested in collecting knowledge and parading
it around as wisdom rather than acting upon it to discover the true nature of that knowledge. Experience is the only
true impartation of wisdom. Everything else is just academic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Working Body Means A Free Mind]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/working-body-means-a-free-mind/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-20T09:17:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/working-body-means-a-free-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spend a vast majority of my week positioned squarely on my butt. It's a sedentary life, which is why I've had to start
working out again, but it's one that I love and get paid to live. Not that I'm not phyically capable of working to earn
a living, it's simply that someone values my mind more than my body at this point. I'm ok with that but I've come to
realize that these two things aren't as separate as I used to think. I have things I do to keep both in line and they
have become way more important as I've grown older (and hopefully wiser).</p>

<p>No, this is not another post about exercise - at least not by the standard definition of that word. It's more about the
things we need to do to exercise our minds and to have "quiet times" for that. I love being outdoors and my favorite activity of the week is mowing the lawn. It's a time for me to do some rote work that frees my mind up to wander and explore.
It's prayer time, reflection time, an opportunity to process and
expand on the ideas banging around inside my head. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='My wife likes to tease me about it being the loudest quiet time imaginable. '> My wife likes to tease me about it being the loudest quiet time imaginable. </span></p>

<p>I realized that this time has allowed me to clarify a lot of my thoughts. It allows me time to think thru what is going
on in my life and work. I can exand ideas and game-film interactions that I know are coming so that the best possible
results can be achieved. Realizing all this led me to a few other interesting thoughts...what would it take to cause me
to hire someone to mow? It's time that I value greatly and would have to replace in some other way to achieve the same
level of thoughtfulness so it's trade off would be a big one. So then, what else can I delegate to allow me to continue
mowing? At this point, I'm not willing to outsource my family or my job so I guess I'll have to keep thinking about it.
While mowing, of course.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Don't Know]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-23T16:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/i-dont-know</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saying "I don't know" is hard. It's an admission of a shortcoming, a lack. It says, "I lack knowledge" or "I lack understanding".
Not saying it is worse though. Making up some sort of answer says the same thing, shows the same lack, but it includes
a lie; an inability to admit reality or be perceived as inadequate. News flash: we all are inadequate (on a way more frequent basis
than we'd like to admit). The difference is you choose to ignore reality. A lack of knowledge is something that could possibly be
remedied. But lying about realities, that's intrinsic, something fundamental and not something that you can easily
fix. Oh, and the person you're talking to will know it - they just might be polite enough not to say anything. Do yourself a favor;
just say "I don't know" and we can both go from there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wear Your Career Uniform]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T08:16:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/wear-your-career-uniform</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few weeks back I had multiple client and business needs that required me to dress up a little more than I usually do.
After enduring the standard, "You got an interview or something?" wise cracks that are inevitable, I began to notice
a change behaviors in a couple of ways. Now I want to be clear, I believe the old maxim, <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;The clothes make the man&#8221; is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. '> "The clothes make the man" is BS. I am not what I wear. I am not my designer label. </span> But...the clothes are an outwards manifestation of something
internal. They don't make you work any harder or be more productive but if your job involves appearances in any way,
you're at a disadvantage. They make people see you in a particular way, like it or not, we are a prejudicial people.
You make snap judgements; everyone does. Fighting reality is futile (but that's another post). Give it a shot yourself
- take 3 weeks and shift how you dress, then see what differences have come up in both your personal attitude and that
  of those around you...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
