<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: thoughts | Driven To Develop]]></title>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/categories/thoughts/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-05T19:39:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://driventodevelop.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David O'Hara]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Accessible]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/be-accessible/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T19:29:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/be-accessible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="/images/open-door.jpg">
Have you ever heard of having an “open door” policy? More than likely. Have you ever found that to be a lie? Sadly, more
than likely. Often times companies, or individuals, like to claim that they have this policy but aren’t truly interested
in being accessible. They believe that given sufficient access, folks would consume all their time and no work would get
done. Not me. <span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='I love to tell people that I’m always available.'> I love to tell people that I’m always available. </span> This breeds trust in
the people that I give that information to; they know they can have access to me anytime they may need it. This doesn’t
mean that I’ll drop everything to talk with them any time they ask but I will make room for them and allow them to help
prioritize their needs in the queue that is my job. Also, that allows me to push the responsibility on to them and trust
that they'll only contact me when needed and not for frivolous things. People don’t like to be a bother and aren’t
looking to waste your time so I don't need to filter them thru anything to be sure they're not wasting time. They seem
to do that on their own. Granted, there are always exceptions and some that are more likely to take advantage but those
are edge cases. And we all know you do your best not to mandate to exceptions; just treat them as exceptions and deal
with them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Controlling Emotion and Mindset]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/controlling-emotion-and-mindset/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-21T11:07:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/controlling-emotion-and-mindset</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Emotion is always a reaction and, therefore, cannot be intentional. Mindsets can be either reactionary or intentional
but intentional is typically better. I say typically because if you were to see a snake in the woods, being reactionary
can be a life saver. But that's not what we're discussing here...</p>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/zen-lotus-position.jpg">
This reactionary bias causes the feelings to cloud what makes most sense or what might be the logically correct course
of action. So how can you control your mindset if you can't see past the emotion?
We cannot prevent our emotional reactions or control ourselves having certain emotions but we can consciously choose
how we act beyond the rise of the emotion. This is the emotional meaning of a situation rather than the invocation of
the emotions themselves. By controlling this, we control the associations that we have with the context that spawned them
and can even increase the likelihood of future contexts creating the emotions we want rather than the ones we don't.</p>

<p>By thinking thru the situation we experienced and the emotions that it brought on and then rationalizing thru the situation
and our expected outcomes, we increase the potential for us to feel differently the next time we experience the same
situation. It's a mental hack! Even more interesting is that we can set ourselves up for this before we head into a
situation. It's called priming and it's been shown to be HUGELY effective in altering the emotions we feel in a situation
regardless of whether or not the situation was emotionally charged.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Always More Efficient]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/always-more-efficient/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-13T08:21:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/always-more-efficient</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em> What is something you should do less efficiently so that you can do it more thoroughly? </em></strong></p>

<p>We are always working to be more efficient - we attempt to multi-task (yes, I know it's a myth that we truly can but
that doesn't seem to stop folks from trying), we optimize our schedules, we plan our meetings to the minute, we are
looking to squeeze every last drop out every minute we have during the day. But at what cost? Often times, we are so
focused on being efficient that we miss important details. We lose the opportunity to truly connect and go deep
because we're so focused on what is coming next. We should be working to squeeze every bit of connection out of those
meetings. Focusing on what we can do really well regardless of the extra effort it takes. We should be more concerned
with the value we are providing than the schedule we are keeping.</p>

<p>This next week, I am intentionally going to focus on at least 1 thing that I will be less efficient at so that I can
be more thorough. Do you know what it is you would focus on?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Time For Work]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/time-for-work/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T07:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/time-for-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Disclaimer</h3>

<p><strong><em> This is a perspective I'm currently exploring and so I'm arguing both sides. You've been warned. </em></strong></p>

<h2>Family</h2>

<p>When we need time for something it must be taken. It cannot be replaced or given back or returned, we consume it and it's gone.
Often times when you need that extra time to get something done, like a meeting or conversation, we steal that time from our families.
We steal from them because they love us and will forgive us. We don't seem to steal that time from the people we work for/with. But why is that?
Our drive to perform or excel, to be perfect at work, overrides our drive to be the same at home.
When I take that extra hour to have another meeting or to finish conversation or do another report, I'm stealing from my son or my wife. This is
an emotional representation rather than a factual one to be clear but that doesn't make it any less accurate. Perceptions are reality.</p>

<h2>Work</h2>

<p>I was made for this. The gifts I have been given, the talents that I possess, the knowledge that I have acquired...all align to what I am doing.
I am fulfilling my purpose. I was made to work and by living up to that potential I am setting an example for my family. The provisions that we have
are because of this effort and we can enjoy them as the blessings that they truly are. When I take the time to make sure a job is done right
I am showing my children how to be diligent in their work.</p>

<p>You can't steal what is given freely. If I put a basket of pennies somewhere with a sign
"Take as many as you need" and you take them all, it wasn't stealing. Often times our families give freely, where our employers do not, and that's
not stealing. This is where the recent trend of "unlimited" vacation time has started to shift that mindset but that's a different post...</p>

<h2>Balance is NOT the goal</h2>

<p>You cannot balance two things that are fundamentally unequal. It's like closing one eye and holding up a yellow M&amp;M until it's the same size as the sun in the sky.
Now they're the same, right? Looking at something thru a single dimensionality is a farce and by no means a measure of that thing. Size alone doesn't make them the same
any more than me spending more time at work than home makes one more significant than the other.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Excel is a Cul-de-sac]]></title>
    <link href="http://driventodevelop.com/blog/excel-is-a-cul-de-sac/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-28T08:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://driventodevelop.com/blog/excel-is-a-cul-de-sac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my recent transition, I've had to become even more intimate with Excel as a tool of my job. Previously I've used Excel
in crazy ways, as a data source for an ODBC connection or a pass thru between disconnected services, but now it's
something to run the business on. That's a knife that cuts both ways though.</p>

<h2>The Current State</h2>

<p>Excel is an extremely useful app and the learning curve on it is fairly low. Things you would typically do are easily
found via Google and most C-level folks have been mashing up formulas for a good hunk of time. I can safely say there
are some companies of significant size that are run off of Excel spreadsheets that are passed around via email
(don't even get me started on the lack of Dropbox use). It works fairly well and, while seemingly creating only a small
amount of overhead, gets the job done. But there's a big problem underlying this behavior.</p>

<h2>The Problem</h2>

<p>New people. Ok, so the new people aren't the actual problem but they surface the start of the problem. When data is pulled from a
source system into Excel it can be sliced, diced, and manipulated until it says what you need it to but that's it. It's
done. And it was almost always manual. Rarely is the manipulation reproducible by anyone other than the person who just
did it because that would require the use of macros and VBScript and stuff that only developers really grok. Strike #1.</p>

<p>Manipulated data is dead in Excel, like those dead tree requirements docs we have all decided were a less
than ideal way to do things. You can't pull new data into the existing spreadsheet and have it follow the transformation to add
to the output. No, instead you pull new data and start back at square one. Strike #2.</p>

<p>Did you want to use that data in some other system or feed it back into the one that it originally came from? No joy
here. The data cannot be consumed in as easy a fashion as it was put into Excel. Sure you can get a developer to monkey
up an ODBC connection like I did before but that's not something most executives are going to be able to pull off.
Maybe they're able to string together a set of Excel sheets that refer to each other and use the data between them but
that's a tangled and fragile web. And given the prior two issues, we know what sort of overhead maintaining that is
going to be when it comes time to update with new data. Strike #3.</p>

<h2>Conclusions</h2>

<p>I'm not against using Excel, heck, I do it on a pretty regular basis. I'm against it's overuse; the crutch that it
becomes when folks just want a one off thing (until it isn't), for just a few people (until there's more), and won't
need again (until they do). When you need something more, step up and move out of your comfort zone, find a tool that
supports what you need and isn't a three strike offender.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
